DMITRY SMYRNOV

Software engineer



+30 697 439 65 11 smyrnovd@gmail.com Thessaloniki, Greece

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Applied Informatics University of Macedonia Thessaloniki, Greece

SKILLS

Visual Basic, SQL database, web frameworks, objectoriented programming, cloud solutions such as AWS and Azure, Java, Docker, Git, Selenium, Java, Python, PHP

Vue, React, NextJS, NodeJS, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS

LANGUAGES

Ukrainian (native) Russia (native) Greek (Fluent) English (advanced)

ABOUT ME

I am a software engineer specializing in technology and financial innovation. With a strong focus on developing software projects, I have successfully created front-end applications for various domains. My ability to quickly adapt and excel in future projects is supported by my high capacity for self-learning.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer, ELTA Courier, Greece. (Jan 2012 - Dec 2012)

Designed and developed a desktop application to collect client information and store it in an SQL database. Successfully managed with Linux distribution.

Automation Engineer, Retailer Chain, Ukraine. (Jan 2013 - Dec 2015)

Responsible for automation, data center, data processing and ERP managing. 3 times faster workflow based on previous 6 years. 1C ERP system also reduced labour and material cost by 30%.

Strategy Manager and Design Executor, Crypto Industry Startup, Ukraine. (Jan 2016 - Dec 2020)

Designed and delivered blockchain solutions and NFTs. Specialised in web application development using the latest frameworks and libraries, AWS cloud solutions.

Frontend Developer, Traders tool, Ukraine. (Jan 2021 - Oct 2022)

Development of a private solution for a cryptocurrency trading company. Implementation of new features that increased the end result by 20%

PROJECTS

MITO Automation SaaS Solution

Designed and deployed serverless application with more than 300 active users. Developed an automation web application that connects e-commerce website with popular product listing markets

Web Development Freelancer, Self-Employed

Developed and launched multiple websites for clients in diverse industries. Implemented back-end functionality using frameworks like WordPress, Drupal, and custom PHP development.

Notification Chat BOT

One of my notable achievements includes developing a chat bot using Python to monitor mining rig status and hashing power. By implementing efficient algorithms and utilizing real-time data, I significantly reduced downtime by several times, ensuring optimal performance and maximizing productivity.